<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Volūmen</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/</link>
<description>Updates and notes from Volūmen</description>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:38:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<atom:link href="https://notes.volumen.ca/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item>
<title>White Christmas</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#white-christmas</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#white-christmas</guid>
<description>I started learning this song in December 2022, approaching it one
phrase at a time and at a very gradual pace in the weeks leading up to
Christmas. In retrospect, I might have chosen a particularly challenging
arrangement, but after dedicating so much time and effort to it, I feel
compelled to...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Unknown</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#unknown</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#unknown</guid>
<description>No description available.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Telecaster</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#telecaster</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#telecaster</guid>
<description>The rosewood fingerboard and the U-shaped maple neck immediately
caught my eye. I recognized this fine instrument instantly; it was the
same Telecaster we had seen during our visit to Tokyo last year. And
now, here I was, holding it in my hands, this time at the Fender
Flagship Store in...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Quiet Mornings</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#quiet-mornings</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#quiet-mornings</guid>
<description>This morning, I experienced deep satisfaction in rediscovering the
tastes, sounds, and sensations I can effortlessly perceive, which
profoundly affect my mind. Many advocate practicing gratitude to achieve
such effects, yet prescriptive approaches may diminish the impact of
these effects....</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>On Handwriting</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#on-handwriting</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#on-handwriting</guid>
<description>The act of using a good pen or pencil overrides the dissatisfaction
one feels from bad-looking handwriting. I currently don’t like how my
handwriting looks; imprecise lettering, frequent errors, and sometimes
crossing out words when I can’t erase them make the written page look
suboptimal. That...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Plateau of Talent</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#the-plateau-of-talent</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#the-plateau-of-talent</guid>
<description>From Haruki Murakami’s novel Kafka on the Shore, (Murakami,
2006) translated into English by Philip Gabriel. The passage
appears in a section where the character Oshima is speaking to Kafka
Tamura about talent, discipline, and what Murakami calls “the plateau of
talent.”</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Too Much of Everything</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#too-much-of-everything</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#too-much-of-everything</guid>
<description>The more plugins you have, the more distracted you become in your
text editor, defeating the purpose of having it in the first place.
Similarly, the more pedals you collect, the farther you drift from
focusing on your playing. Ironically, the very tools meant to help you
make music end up...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uses</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#uses</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#uses</guid>
<description>When I seek guidance, I turn to books. Classical philosophy and
strategy teach leadership and discipline, especially during workplace
challenges (Machiavelli,
1998; Musashi, 2005; L. Tzu &amp; Needleman, 1989; S. Tzu, 2005).
The Stoics highlight life’s fragility (Aurelius,
2003; Seneca, 1997)....</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fake News</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#fake-news</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#fake-news</guid>
<description>The greatest worry about the idea of fake news isn’t actually that
people believe false news - it’s that they stop believing real news. Phillips (2020)</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Compound Effect</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#the-compound-effect</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#the-compound-effect</guid>
<description>I came across this interesting thought on the internet: Consistent
daily writing yields a book in a year, while sporadic efforts result in
scattered fragments. The impact is profound. The initial effort feels
heavy, the first page slow, and the first video awkward, but each effort
lays...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Corb Lund</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#corb-lund</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#corb-lund</guid>
<description>Corb Lund, a Canadian country and western singer-songwriter from
Taber, Alberta, performed a great rendition of Bob Dylan’s ‘I Shall Be
Released’ on Tuff Radio this morning. He’s released twelve albums, with
three certified gold. Lund tours regularly in Canada, the US, and
Australia, winning...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Seneca Effect</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#seneca-effect</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#seneca-effect</guid>
<description>The Seneca Effect (Bardi, 2017), as explained
by Ugo Bardi, views complex systems through a systems-thinking lens.
Drawing on Seneca’s observation that ”increases are of sluggish growth,
but the way to ruin is rapid,” the book suggests that systems grow
gradually but collapse swiftly due to...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Imperfection</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#imperfection</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#imperfection</guid>
<description>I once came across this thought, though I can’t recall where: regrets
belong to the past, and anxieties to the future. One cannot be at peace
with life without truly living it. The past is fixed, the future
uncertain and often overwhelming. The mind wrestles with both, but the
solution is...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nuances</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#nuances</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#nuances</guid>
<description>Quiet your mind to hear the nuances in the notes. Slowing down and
calming the mind unveils hidden harmonies, textures, and rhythms. While
this is a learning exercise, it also yields a delightful surprise in the
resultant sounds.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Durability</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#durability</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#durability</guid>
<description>When it comes to tools, I prefer those that strike a balance between
durability and simplicity. Durable tools endure wear and tear, ensuring
their longevity and maximizing the value of investment. Simplicity in
design and usage makes tasks easier and more efficient. I value tools
that are both...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Practice as Performance</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice-as-performance</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice-as-performance</guid>
<description>I recorded my Week 8 performance, which proceeded smoothly. I have
modified my approach by not recording every exercise, instead focusing
on daily guitar practice and study. On Day 7, following a breathing
session, I played continuously without stopping for mistakes, recording
the full set in a...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>One and Done</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#one-and-done</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#one-and-done</guid>
<description>I find myself increasingly drawn to a “one-and-done” philosophy when
it comes to worldly possessions. There’s a quiet realization that I
don’t have enough time to truly experience or make good use of the
things I have, like pens, guitars, and other tools. It seems that to
understand something...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Asymmetries</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#asymmetries</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#asymmetries</guid>
<description>I noticed certain asymmetries that govern the relationship between
positive and negative outcomes—for example effort versus gain;
especially once a critical point has been passed, such as the point of
diminishing returns.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Short-termism</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#short-termism</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#short-termism</guid>
<description>Darwin (Darwin, 2003) documented any information that contradicted his evolving theories and
conclusions. He recognized confirmation bias long before it had a name
and developed a practical system to counteract it. I try to do the same
when reading or listening to podcasts. Here’s an idea that...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Practice</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice</guid>
<description>Practice with discipline, but without friction, maintaining a calm
and steady approach. Take each step deliberately to enter the flow state
where progress unfolds. Though progress is not the goal, it arises as a
consequence of unintended outcomes. This is the ultimate state of mind,
the one that...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
