<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Volūmen</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/</link>
<description>Updates and notes from Volūmen</description>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 20:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<atom:link href="https://notes.volumen.ca/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item>
<title>Fake News</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#fake-news</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#fake-news</guid>
<description>The greatest worry about the idea of fake news isn’t actually that
people believe false news - it’s that they stop believing real news. Phillips (2020)</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Compound Effect</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#the-compound-effect</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#the-compound-effect</guid>
<description>I came across this interesting thought on the internet: Consistent
daily writing yields a book in a year, while sporadic efforts result in
scattered fragments. The impact is profound. The initial effort feels
heavy, the first page slow, and the first video awkward, but each effort
lays...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Corb Lund</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#corb-lund</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#corb-lund</guid>
<description>Corb Lund, a Canadian country and western singer-songwriter from
Taber, Alberta, performed a great rendition of Bob Dylan’s ‘I Shall Be
Released’ on Tuff Radio this morning. He’s released twelve albums, with
three certified gold. Lund tours regularly in Canada, the US, and
Australia, winning...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Seneca Effect</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#seneca-effect</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#seneca-effect</guid>
<description>The Seneca Effect (Bardi, 2017), as explained
by Ugo Bardi, views complex systems through a systems-thinking lens.
Drawing on Seneca’s observation that ”increases are of sluggish growth,
but the way to ruin is rapid,” the book suggests that systems grow
gradually but collapse swiftly due to...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Imperfection</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#imperfection</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#imperfection</guid>
<description>I once came across this thought, though I can’t recall where: regrets
belong to the past, and anxieties to the future. One cannot be at peace
with life without truly living it. The past is fixed, the future
uncertain and often overwhelming. The mind wrestles with both, but the
solution is...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uses</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#uses</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#uses</guid>
<description>When I seek guidance, I turn to books. Classical philosophy and
strategy teach leadership and discipline, especially during workplace
challenges (Machiavelli,
1998; Musashi, 2005; L. Tzu &amp; Needleman, 1989; S. Tzu, 2005).
The Stoics highlight life’s fragility (Aurelius,
2003; Seneca, 1997)....</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nuances</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#nuances</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#nuances</guid>
<description>Quiet your mind to hear the nuances in the notes. Slowing down and
calming the mind unveils hidden harmonies, textures, and rhythms. While
this is a learning exercise, it also yields a delightful surprise in the
resultant sounds.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Durability</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#durability</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#durability</guid>
<description>When it comes to tools, I prefer those that strike a balance between
durability and simplicity. Durable tools endure wear and tear, ensuring
their longevity and maximizing the value of investment. Simplicity in
design and usage makes tasks easier and more efficient. I value tools
that are both...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Practice as Performance</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice-as-performance</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice-as-performance</guid>
<description>I recorded my Week 8 performance, which proceeded smoothly. I have
modified my approach by not recording every exercise, instead focusing
on daily guitar practice and study. On Day 7, following a breathing
session, I played continuously without stopping for mistakes, recording
the full set in a...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>One and Done</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#one-and-done</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#one-and-done</guid>
<description>I find myself increasingly drawn to a “one-and-done” philosophy when
it comes to worldly possessions. There’s a quiet realization that I
don’t have enough time to truly experience or make good use of the
things I have, like pens, guitars, and other tools. It seems that to
understand something...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Asymmetries</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#asymmetries</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#asymmetries</guid>
<description>I noticed certain asymmetries that govern the relationship between
positive and negative outcomes—for example effort versus gain;
especially once a critical point has been passed, such as the point of
diminishing returns.</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Short-termism</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#short-termism</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#short-termism</guid>
<description>Darwin (Darwin, 2003) documented any information that contradicted his evolving theories and
conclusions. He recognized confirmation bias long before it had a name
and developed a practical system to counteract it. I try to do the same
when reading or listening to podcasts. Here’s an idea that...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Practice</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice</guid>
<description>Practice with discipline, but without friction, maintaining a calm
and steady approach. Take each step deliberately to enter the flow state
where progress unfolds. Though progress is not the goal, it arises as a
consequence of unintended outcomes. This is the ultimate state of mind,
the one that...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ordinary Sights</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#ordinary-sights</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#ordinary-sights</guid>
<description>When we travel, there is almost no downtime as we hop from one place
to another. Exploration is wonderful. Seeing extraordinary places,
nature, and culture often leaves us in overwhelming awe, yet these
moments tend to slip away with time, leaving only fragments in our
long-term memory. What is...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intuition</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#intuition</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#intuition</guid>
<description>Daniel Kahneman said most people make quick judgments and then try to
prove themselves right. The wisest wait, gather facts, and trust their
intuition last.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reflection Cultivates Intuition</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#reflection-cultivates-intuition</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#reflection-cultivates-intuition</guid>
<description>Reflect on what you’ve read and written. Information becomes
knowledge by reflection. Reflection cultivates intuition. Abundant
intuition makes up for the lack of information, thereby enabling you to
operate where your knowledge is limited.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Art of Translation</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#the-art-of-translation</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#the-art-of-translation</guid>
<description>Borges wrote and lectured extensively on the art of translation,
holding that a translation may improve upon the original, may even be
unfaithful to it, and that alternative and potentially contradictory
renderings of the same work can be equally valid.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sustain or cycle</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#sustain-or-cycle</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#sustain-or-cycle</guid>
<description>The longer you remain seated and focus on a task, the shallower you
breathe, and the less oxygen gets to your brain. Therefore, quickly step
away from your work and cycle your attention every 20 minutes. Quickly
stepping away from your work to get a drink of water, walk around the
block, or go...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Truth, Lies &amp; Deception</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#truth-lies--deception</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#truth-lies--deception</guid>
<description>A Turkish proverb says, “A fool may throw a stone into a well that a
hundred wise men cannot pull out.” Inspired by this, one observation is,
“One lie cannot be undone by forty truths.” Both express that a single
careless act can have severe consequences, even with effort and truth.
They...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Clarity, Ease &amp; Refinement</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#clarity-ease--refinement</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#clarity-ease--refinement</guid>
<description>Concision is to mind what cleanliness is to the body. Concision, like
cleanliness, plays a crucial role in personal and professional life.
Just as cleanliness eliminates dirt and clutter from the body, concision
eliminates unnecessary words and ideas from communication, leaving
behind clear,...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
