<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Volūmen</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/</link>
<description>Updates and notes from Volūmen</description>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 21:00:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<atom:link href="https://notes.volumen.ca/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item>
<title>Bullshit Jobs</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#bullshit-jobs</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#bullshit-jobs</guid>
<description>## Lessons from the Book  Many jobs are pointless or most jobs have elements of pointless activities. Pay attention to the people and the positions they hold. If you identify any of the five types, do not waste your precious time. Most importantly if you discover your job is nothing but bs, you must...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 20:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Colophon</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#colophon</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#colophon</guid>
<description>Volūmen is built with [Pandoc](https://pandoc.org), [Python](https://www.python.org), and the Courier monospace typeface....</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 20:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uses</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#uses</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#uses</guid>
<description>When I seek guidance, I turn to books. Classical philosophy and strategy teach leadership and discipline, especially during workplace challenges [@musashiBookFiveRings2005; @tzuArtWar2005; @tzuTaoTeChing1989; @machiavelliPrince1998]. The Stoics highlight life’s fragility [@senecaShortnessLifeOther19...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nuances</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#nuances</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#nuances</guid>
<description>Quiet your mind to hear the nuances in the notes. Slowing down and calming the mind unveils hidden harmonies, textures, and rhythms. While this is a learning exercise, it also yields a delightful surprise in the resultant sounds....</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Durability</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#durability</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#durability</guid>
<description>When it comes to tools, I prefer those that strike a balance between durability and simplicity. Durable tools endure wear and tear, ensuring their longevity and maximizing the value of investment. Simplicity in design and usage makes tasks easier and more efficient. I value tools that are both durab...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Practice as Performance</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice-as-performance</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice-as-performance</guid>
<description>I recorded my Week 8 performance, which proceeded smoothly. I have modified my approach by not recording every exercise, instead focusing on daily guitar practice and study. On Day 7, following a breathing session, I played continuously without stopping for mistakes, recording the full set in a sing...</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Asymmetries</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#asymmetries</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#asymmetries</guid>
<description>I noticed certain asymmetries that govern the relationship between positive and negative outcomes—for example effort versus gain; especially once a critical point has been passed, such as the point of diminishing returns.  The Pareto distribution provides another example of this kind of asymmetry (r...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>One and Done</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#one-and-done</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#one-and-done</guid>
<description>I find myself increasingly drawn to a “one-and-done” philosophy when it comes to worldly possessions. There’s a quiet realization that I don’t have enough time to truly experience or make good use of the things I have, like pens, guitars, and other tools. It seems that to understand something deeply...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Short-termism</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#short-termism</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#short-termism</guid>
<description>Darwin [@darwinAutobiographyCharlesDarwin2003] documented any information that contradicted his evolving theories and conclusions. He recognized confirmation bias long before it had a name and developed a practical system to counteract it. I try to do the same when reading or listening to podcasts....</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Practice</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#practice</guid>
<description>Practice with discipline, but without friction, maintaining a calm and steady approach. Take each step deliberately to enter the flow state where progress unfolds. Though progress is not the goal, it arises as a consequence of unintended outcomes. This is the ultimate state of mind, the one that bri...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
