<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Volūmen</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/</link>
<description>Updates and notes from Volūmen</description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 08:49:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<atom:link href="https://notes.volumen.ca/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item>
<title>Dependencies</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#dependencies</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#dependencies</guid>
<description>Sometimes we create unnecessary dependencies that quietly shape our
workflow, causing delays, friction, and anxiety. Like premature
optimization, adding structure before it’s needed can actively work
against the work itself. The more conditions that must align before
progress is possible, the...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pareto Principle</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#pareto-principle</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#pareto-principle</guid>
<description>The Pareto Principle, also known as the “80:20 rule,” asserts that
80% of outcomes stem from 20% of causes. Named after the Italian
polymath Vilfredo Pareto, the principle is supported by empirical
observation showing that this 80:20 distribution applies to a wide
variety of situations,...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>On Stupidty</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#on-stupidty</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#on-stupidty</guid>
<description>The basic laws assert that, according to Cipolla (Cipolla,
2019) : 1. Everyone inevitably underestimates the number of stupid
individuals in circulation. 2. The probability of an individual being
stupid is independent of any characteristic of that person. 3. A stupid
person is one who causes...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>On Bullshit</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#on-bullshit</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#on-bullshit</guid>
<description>Bullshit is a technical term, and Harry Frankfurt’s book (Frankfurt,
2005) is probably the best reference for it. When someone lies,
they knowingly misrepresent the truth. However, when someone bullshits,
they don’t care about the truth; they simply say whatever is necessary
to achieve their...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Now</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#now</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#now</guid>
<description>I am currently focused solely on transitioning from my current job to
my new one. While it is not a huge task, it is taking a lot of mental
energy. If I had had less time before the transfer, it would have been
much easier, being a completionist making it more difficult than it
should be.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scenes From Above</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#scenes-from-above</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#scenes-from-above</guid>
<description>Julian Lage quietly released a new album, Scenes From Above, on
January 23, 2026. The music is wonderful, and it’s especially special
because it features another talented musician, the keyboardist John
Medeski. We also get to enjoy his long-term bandmates, the bassist Jorge
Roeder and the...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Way *and* the Highway</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#my-way-and-the-highway</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#my-way-and-the-highway</guid>
<description>Man makes tools. In turn, tools make a different man through his
work. Neither the man nor the tool remains the same; they are forever
transformed, locked in a reciprocal process of mutual becoming, thereby
perpetually evolving.</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ever So Slowly</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#ever-so-slowly</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#ever-so-slowly</guid>
<description>During one summer, I had the opportunity to review my guitar
practices that I recorded since 2018 and a few earlier than that. I
named the playlist Ever So Slowly, because it’s been such a
slow process for me to make progress on the guitar. That said, the
playlist also demonstrates the fact that...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rick Rubin</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#rick-rubin</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#rick-rubin</guid>
<description>Rick Rubin is a remarkable man who has produced such notable artists
as Johnny Cash and Jake Bugg. I recently came across The Way of Code (Anthropic,
n.d.), in which he notes, “Each encounter I’ve had with Lao Tzu
has pointed to something new. Almost as if the book changes with every
reading. I...</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>2025</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#2025</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#2025</guid>
<description>Another year is about to conclude. It passed like we inhaled a breath
of fresh air yesterday, and today we are exhaling it, a little tired but
filled with hope and excitement. Looking back, the year has been,
despite its tiring parts, also full of joyful periods, growth, and
satisfaction.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Emptiness</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#emptiness</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#emptiness</guid>
<description>Clay transforms into pottery through craft, but it’s the emptiness
within that makes a pot truly useful. What’s absent can be just as
significant as what’s present. This idea originates from the Tao Te
Ching, a foundational text of Taoism. (Tzu &amp; Needleman, 1989)</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>White Christmas</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#white-christmas</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#white-christmas</guid>
<description>I started learning this song in December 2022, approaching it one
phrase at a time and at a very gradual pace in the weeks leading up to
Christmas. In retrospect, I might have chosen a particularly challenging
arrangement, but after dedicating so much time and effort to it, I feel
compelled to...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Notes</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#notes</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#notes</guid>
<description>No description available.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Telecaster</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#telecaster</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#telecaster</guid>
<description>The rosewood fingerboard and the U-shaped maple neck immediately
caught my eye. I recognized this fine instrument instantly; it was the
same Telecaster we had seen during our visit to Tokyo last year. And
now, here I was, holding it in my hands, this time at the Fender
Flagship Store in...</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Quiet Mornings</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#quiet-mornings</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#quiet-mornings</guid>
<description>This morning, I experienced deep satisfaction in rediscovering the
tastes, sounds, and sensations I can effortlessly perceive, which
profoundly affect my mind. Many advocate practicing gratitude to achieve
such effects, yet prescriptive approaches may diminish the impact of
these effects....</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>On Handwriting</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#on-handwriting</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#on-handwriting</guid>
<description>The act of using a good pen or pencil overrides the dissatisfaction
one feels from bad-looking handwriting. I currently don’t like how my
handwriting looks; imprecise lettering, frequent errors, and sometimes
crossing out words when I can’t erase them make the written page look
suboptimal. That...</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Plateau of Talent</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#the-plateau-of-talent</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#the-plateau-of-talent</guid>
<description>From Haruki Murakami’s novel Kafka on the Shore, (Murakami,
2006) translated into English by Philip Gabriel. The passage
appears in a section where the character Oshima is speaking to Kafka
Tamura about talent, discipline, and what Murakami calls “the plateau of
talent.”</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Too Much of Everything</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#too-much-of-everything</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#too-much-of-everything</guid>
<description>The more plugins you have, the more distracted you become in your
text editor, defeating the purpose of having it in the first place.
Similarly, the more pedals you collect, the farther you drift from
focusing on your playing. Ironically, the very tools meant to help you
make music end up...</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Uses</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#uses</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#uses</guid>
<description>When I seek guidance, I turn to books. Classical philosophy and
strategy teach leadership and discipline, especially during workplace
challenges. The Stoics highlight life’s fragility. Modern thought
provides clarity through mindfulness practices, philosophical inquiry,
science revealing hidden...</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fake News</title>
<link>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#fake-news</link>
<guid>https://notes.volumen.ca/index.html#fake-news</guid>
<description>The greatest worry about the idea of fake news isn’t actually that
people believe false news - it’s that they stop believing real news. Phillips (2020)</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
